Already know, let's add one more layer of complexity,
下面增加一下难度系数
by using a factor model to describe a portfolio of stocks.
我们使用因子模型来描述股票投资组合
A portfolio's return can also be modeled as a sum of two parts,
投资组合的收益率也可以表示为两个部分的和
the returns that can be explained by a set of factors,
即一组因子能够解释的收益率
and the returns that are specific to each stock within the portfolio.
加上投资组合中每支股票特有的收益率
Let's look at a single factors contribution to the portfolio.
我们看看单个因子对投资组合的贡献
Assuming we had the factor exposures of each stock within the portfolio,
假设我们知道投资组合中每支股票的因子暴露度
and we also had the weight of each stock in the portfolio,
并且知道每支股票的权重
how do we get the portfolios factor exposure?
如何计算投资组合因子暴露度？
Well, a portfolio's exposure to a factor is
投资组合对因子的暴露度等于
a weighted average of the exposures from his individual stocks.
各支股票的暴露度加权平均值
For each stock in the portfolio,
对于投资组合中的每支股票
we multiply the stocks portfolio weight,
我们将股票的投资组合权重
by that stocks exposure to that factor,
乘以该股票对该因子的暴露度
and we sum up all these weighted Betas.
并将所有这些加权 β 相加
This process may look familiar to you.
这个流程也许看起来熟悉
We do the same with portfolio returns,
投资组合收益率也是这么计算的
by calculating a weighted average of the individual stock returns.
即单个股票收益率的加权平均值
The difference here is that we're calculating the portfolio's factor exposure,
区别在于我们计算的是投资组合的因子暴露度
instead of the portfolio's returns.
而不是投资组合的收益率
So, now we can get the portfolio's exposure to one factor,
现在我们可以计算投资组合对一个因子的暴露度
exposure to a second factor,
对第二个因子的暴露度
and exposures to each factor in the model.
以及对模型中每个因子的暴露度
If we have each factors contribution to the portfolio return,
如果我们知道每个因子对投资组合收益率的贡献
we can sum up the contributions of all the factors.
我们可以将所有因子的贡献加起来
The remaining part of the portfolio's return is the specific return.
投资组合收益率的剩下部分是特有收益率
Can you think of how to get the portfolios specific return,
如果知道每支股票的特有收益率
if we have the specific return of each stock?
该如何计算投资组合的特有收益率？
The portfolio's specific return is the weighted sum of the specific return of each stock.
投资组合的特有收益率等于每支股票的特有收益率加权和
So, we take each stock's weight in the portfolio,
我们用每支股票的权重
multiplied by the stock's specific return,
乘以股票的特有收益率
and add this up for all stocks in the portfolio.
然后将它们加起来
This weighted sum is the portfolio's specific return.
这个加权和就是投资组合的特有收益率
This is the portfolio's return,
这是用因子表示的
modeled in terms of factors.
投资组合收益率
The point is to explain most of the portfolio return,
目的是用一组公共因子
using a set of common factors.
解释投资组合的大部分收益率
Ideally, the chosen factors would explain more of the portfolio return,
理想情况下 所选的因子能够解释投资组合收益率的更多部分
and the specific return would explain less.
特有收益率能够解释更少的部分
From here, we'll get the portfolio's variance,
然后 我们将用这些公共因子
modelled in terms of these common factors.
表示投资组合的方差
We'll look at how to model portfolio variance for the rest of this lesson.
我们将在剩下的课程中讲解如何对投资组合方差建模